RG 004:095, New London Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
New London Probate Court records
1675-1930
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (New London District)
108.75 cubic feet
Record books, 1675-1930; Probate files, 1675-1899.
RG004_095
1912-006, 1977-008, 2011-048
Historical Note
New London, New London County, Town settled in 1646, City incorporated January 1784
New London Probate District was constituted May session, 1666, as a County Court. The New London Probate District presently serves the municipalities of New London and Waterford.
The New London Probate District also included the following municipalities at various times:
Canterbury, October 1703 - October 1719
Colchester, 1698 - October 1708
Deep River (Saybrook), October 1719 - May 1780
East Lyme, May 1839 - June 1, 1843
Groton, May 1705 - October 1766
Killingworth, 1667 - October 1719
Lebanon, October 1700 - October 1719
Lyme, 1667 - June 1830
Montville, October 1786 - June 26, 1851
Norwich, May 1666 - October 1748
Plainfield, May 1699 - October 1719
Preston, October 1687 - October 1748
Salem, May 1819 - July 8, 1841 (part taken from Lyme, from 1824-1841 also part taken from Montville)
Stonington, May 1666 - October 1666
Voluntown, May 1698 - May 1726
Windham, May 1692 - October 1748
City of New London, Probate District chronology:
1646 - May 1666, Colonial Jurisdiction at Hartford and later at new London
May 1666 - Present, New London County Court & District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, 1675-1930. Contact the probate court to access record books after Volume 46 for Records and Volume 46 for Journals. Volumes titled "Journal" record the proceedings of the court. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1675-1899. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Inventory control book, 1675-1850 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Record books are numbered as follows: Records, A-I then 1-46; Journals, 1-46; Wills, 1-6. There is also an unnumbered Wills and distribution volume.
Probate files arranged by accession and alphabetically therein.
Other Finding Aid
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1912-006, covering 1675-1850, and 1977-008, covering 1850-1899, are represented in this index. -1899 cards are generally only dated for those surnames prior to Bassett. There is an additional slip index for New London County Court records volumes 1-7, 1667-1700, found in the genealogical index corridor of the History & Genealogy reading room.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Canterbury; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Colchester; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Deep River; Probate records -- Connecticut -- East Lyme; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Groton; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Killingworth; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Lebanon; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Lyme; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Montville; Probate records -- Connecticut -- New London; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Norwich; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Plainfield; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Preston; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Salem; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Stonington; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Voluntown; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Windham
Places:
Canterbury (Conn.); Colchester (Conn.); Deep River (Conn.); East Lyme (Conn.); Groton (Conn.); Killingworth (Conn.); Lebanon (Conn.); Lyme (Conn.); Montville (Conn.); New London (Conn.); Norwich (Conn.); Plainfield (Conn.); Preston (Conn.); Salem (Conn.); Stonington (Conn.); Voluntown (Conn.); Windham (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Accession 2011-048, Record books, 1675-1930, are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes A-I and 1-40, 1675-1915 and Wills, volumes 1-4, 1890-1925; probate files, 1675-1850; and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the. Volumes of Journals were not microfilmed.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1912-006 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): July 23, 1912 (1675-1850).
The probate files in accession 1977-008 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on March 14, 1977.
The record books in accession 2011-048 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on November 22, 2010 and January 31, 2011.
Container List
- Record books, 1675-1930; 63 cubic feet (118 volumes); 2011-048
  Volumes A through I are not the original record books. It appears the information was copied into these record books between 1895 and 1899.
  - Records, 1675-1713 (Volume A)
  - Records, 1713-1725 (Volume B)
  - Records, 1725-1734 (Volume C)
  - Records, 1734-1742 (Volume D)
  - Records, 1742-1749 (Volume E)
  - Records, 1749-1761 (Volume F)
  - Records, 1749-1761 (Volume G)
  - Records, 1761-1768 (Volume H)
  - Records, 1769-1777 (Volume I)
  - Records, 1781-1786 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1786-1794 (Volume 2)
  - Records, 1794-1798 (Volume 3)
  - Records, 1799-1801 (Volume 4)
  - Records, 1802-1806 (Volume 5)
  - Records, 1806-1811 (Volume 6)
  - Records, 1811-1818 (Volume 7)
  - Records, 1818-1824 (Volume 8)
  - Records, 1825-1834 (Volume 9)
  - Records, 1834-1839 (Volume 10)
  - Records, 1845-1852 (Volume 11)
  - Records, 1852-1858 (Volume 12)
  - Records, 1858-1862 (Volume 13)
  - Records, 1861-1866 (Volume 14)
  - Records, 1866-1871 (Volume 15)
  - Records, 1871-1875 (Volume 16)
  - Records, 1875-1878 (Volume 17)
  - Records, 1878-1881 (Volume 18)
  - Records, 1881-1883 (Volume 19)
  - Records, 1883-1885 (Volume 20)
  - Records, 1885-1888 (Volume 21)
  - Records, 1888-1890 (Volume 22)
  - Records, 1890-1892 (Volume 23)
  - Returns, 1890-1899 (Volume 24)
  - Records, 1892-1893 (Volume 25)
  - Records, 1894-1896 (Volume 26)
  - Records, 1897-1899 (Volume 27)
  - Returns, 1899-1906 (Volume 28)
  - Records, 1900-1902 (Volume 29)
  - Records, 1902-1905 (Volume 30)
  - Records, 1905-1907 (Volume 31)
  - Returns, 1906-1911 (Volume 32)
  - Records, 1907-1908 (Volume 33)
  - Records, 1908-1909 (Volume 34)
  - Records, 1909-1910 (Volume 35)
  - Records, 1910-1912 (Volume 36)
  - Returns, 1911-1916 (Volume 37)
  - Records, 1912-1914 (Volume 38)
  - Records, 1914-1915 (Volume 39)
  - Records, 1915 (Volume 40)
  - Records, 1915-1916 (Volume 41)
  - Records, 1916-1918 (Volume 42)
  - Records, 1911-1928 (Volume 43)
  - Records, 1918-1919 (Volume 44)
  - Records, 1919-1920 (Volume 45)
  - Records, 1920-1921 (Volume 46)
  - Records, 1920-1921 (Volume 46)
  - Journal, 1700-1705 (Volume 1)
  - Journal, 1716-1722 (Volume 2)
  - Journal, 1722-1735 (Volume 3)
  - Journal, 1735-1742 (Volume 4)
  - Journal, 1742-1754 (Volume 5)
  - Journal, 1754-1763 (Volume 6)
  - Journal, 1781-1785 (Volume 6A)
  - Journal, 1785-1798 (Volume 7)
  - Journal, 1798-1809 (Volume 8)
  - Journal, 1809-1824 (Volume 9)
  - Journal, 1825-1835 (Volume 10)
  - Journal, 1835-1842 (Volume 11)
  - Journal, 1842-1850 (Volume 12)
  - Journal, 1850-1857 (Volume 13)
  - Journal, 1857-1860 (Volume 14)
  - Journal, 1860-1863 (Volume 15)
  - Journal, 1863-1868 (Volume 16)
  - Journal, 1868-1871 (Volume 17)
  - Journal, 1871-1874 (Volume 18)
  - Journal, 1873-1876 (Volume 19)
  - Journal, 1875-1880 (Volume 20)
  - Journal, 1879 (Volume 21)
  - Journal, 1883 (Volume 22)
  - Journal, 1888-1923 (Volume 23)
  - Journal, Insolvent estates, 1890 (Volume 24)
  - Journal, Solvent estates of deceased persons, 1892-1903 (Volume 25)
  - Journal, Trustees, guardians, conservators, etc., 1893-1907 (Volume 26)
  - Journal, Solvent estates of deceased persons, 1893-1904 (Volume 27)
  - Journal, Solvent estates of deceased persons, 1895-1907 (Volume 28)
  - Journal, Solvent estates of deceased persons, 1897-1909 (Volume 29)
  - Journal, Solvent estates of deceased persons, 1899 (Volume 30)
  - Journal, Solvent estates of deceased persons, 1901 (Volume 31)
  - Journal, Solvent estates of deceased persons, 1903 (Volume 32)
  - Journal, Solvent estates of deceased persons, 1905-1906 (Volume 33)
  - Journal, Solvent estates of deceased persons, 1906 (Volume 34)
  - Journal, Solvent estates of deceased persons, 1907-1909 (Volume 35)
  - Journal, Trustees, guardians, conservators, etc., 1908-1917 (Volume 36)
  - Journal, Solvent estates of deceased persons, 1908-1910 (Volume 37)
  - Journal, Solvent estates of deceased persons, 1910-1912 (Volume 38)
  - Journal, Solvent estates of deceased persons, 1912-1913 (Volume 39)
  - Journal, Solvent estates of deceased persons, 1914-1915 (Volume 40)
  - Journal, Solvent estates of deceased persons, 1915-1916 (Volume 41)
  - Journal, Solvent estates of deceased persons, 1916-1918 (Volume 42)
  - Journal, Trustees, guardians, conservators, etc., 1911-1928 (Volume 43)
  - Journal, Solvent estates of deceased persons, 1918-1919 (Volume 44)
  - Journal, Solvent estates of deceased persons, 1919-1920 (Volume 45)
  - Journal, Solvent estates of deceased persons, 1920-1921 (Volume 46)
  - Wills and distributions, 1856-1864 (Volume unnumbered)
  - Wills, 1890-1903 (Volume 1)
  - Wills, 1903-1911 (Volume 2)
  - Wills, 1909 (Volume 3)
  - Wills, 1919-1925 (Volume 4)
  - Wills, 1926-1930 (Volume 5)
  - Wills, 1930 (Volume 6)
  - Bonds, 1881-1891 (Volume 1)
  - Bonds, 1892 (Volume 2)
  - Bonds, 1899-1906 (Volume 3)
  - Bonds, 1906-1913 (Volume 4)
  - Bonds, 1917-1918 (Volume 5)
  - Bonds, 1919-1923 (Volume 6)
  - Docket of insane commitment, 1889 (Volume 1)
  - Index of docket of insane commitment (Volume unnumbered)
  - Indigent & pauper, insane poor (Volume unnumbered)
- Probate files, 1675-1850; 27.25 cubic feet; 1912-006
  - Abel - Atwell (Drawer 1)
  - Atwood - Birchard (Drawer 2)
  - Bishop - Calkins, I. (Drawer 3)
  - Calkins, J. - Colver (Drawer 4)
  - Colt - Day, G. (Drawer 5)
  - Day, H. - Ely (Drawer 6)
  - Emerson - Gifford (Drawer 7)
  - Gilbert - Harding (Drawer 8)
  - Harper - Harris, U. (Drawer 9)
  - Harris, V - Hayton (Drawer 10)
  - Hazard - Hill, I. (Drawer 11)
  - Hill, J. - Holt, C. (Drawer 12)
  - Holt, D. - Hull (Drawer 13)
  - Hunn - Hurlburt, J. (Drawer 14)
  - Hurlburt, K. - Johnson, I. (Drawer 15)
  - Johnson, J. - Kelly (Drawer 16)
  - Kelro - Latham (Drawer 17)
  - Latimer - Lay, E. (Drawer 18)
  - Lay, F. - Lee, R. (Drawer 19)
  - Lee, S. - Lepard (Drawer 20)
  - Lester - Liveen (Drawer 21)
  - Livingston - Lord, R. (Drawer 22)
  - Lord, S. - MacCurdy, C. (Drawer 23)
  - MacCurdy, D. - Mallison (Drawer 24)
  - Mallory - Maples (Drawer 25)
  - Marchand - Mather, G. (Drawer 26)
  - Mather, H. - Merrihew (Drawer 27)
  - Merrill - Miner, C. (Drawer 28)
  - Miner, D. - Miner, Z. (Drawer 29)
  - Mitchell - Morgan (Drawer 30)
  - Morris - Niles (Drawer 31)
  - Nobles - Page (Drawer 32)
  - Paine - Park, R. (Drawer 33)
  - Park, S. - Peck, H. (Drawer 34)
  - Peck, I. - Penniman (Drawer 35)
  - Pennock - Pierce (Drawer 36)
  - Pierpont - Powers (Drawer 37)
  - Pratt - Ranger (Drawer 38)
  - Ransom - Read, G. (Drawer 39)
  - Read, H. - Richards, R. (Drawer 40)
  - Richards, S. - Rogers, A. (Drawer 41)
  - Rogers, B. - Rogers, I. (Drawer 42)
  - Rogers, J. - Rogers, K. (Drawer 43)
  - Rogers, L. - Rose, D. (Drawer 44)
  - Rose, E. - Ryon, M. (Drawer 45)
  - Ryon, N. - Scollard (Drawer 46)
  - Scott - Sharp (Drawer 47)
  - Sharswood - Sill, J. (Drawer 48)
  - Sill, K. - Smith, C. (Drawer 49)
  - Smith, D. - Smith, Jonathan (Drawer 50)
  - Smith, Joseph - Smith, R. (Drawer 51)
  - Smith, S. - Spicer, R. (Drawer 52)
  - Spicer, S. - Starr, C. (Drawer 53)
  - Starr, D. - Steel (Drawer 54)
  - Stephenson - Stewart, R. (Drawer 55)
  - Stewart, S. - Street (Drawer 56)
  - Strickland - Terrill, J. (Drawer 57)
  - Terrill, K. - Wade, G. (Drawer 58)
  - Wade, H. - Whipple, S. (Drawer 59)
  - Whipple, T. - Woodward (Drawer 60)
  - Woodworth - Zoega; Miscellaneous (Drawer 61)
- Inventory Control Book, 1675-1850; T003073
  Index of the four accessions of probate files now merged into accession 1912-006
  Date span is coverage
  Also known as the Godard Digest
- Probate files, 1850-1899; 18.5 cubic feet; 1977-008
  Arrangement is roughly alphbetical.
  - Index, 1 volume
  - Abbott - Atwood (Box 1)
  - Ansant - Beckwith, A. (Box 2)
  - Beckwith, B. - Bills, C. (Box 3)
  - Bills, H. - Brooks (Box 4)
  - Brown - Burrows, R. (Box 5)
  - Burrows, S. - Champlain, Henry (Box 6)
  - Camplain, Henry - Chichester (Box 7)
  - Childs - Cowstock, L. (Box 8)
  - Cowstock, H. - Crocker, H. (Box 9)
  - Crocker, S. - Dart, Erastus C. (Box 10)
  - Dart, Erastus C. - Domell (Box 11)
  - Donahue - Falvey (Box 12)
  - Famming - Fuller (Box 13)
  - Fuller - Goddard, H. (Box 14)
  - Goddard, L. - Harris, Elizabeth (Box 15)
  - Harris, Eltie - Hobron (Box 16)
  - Heath - Holloway (Box 17)
  - Holmes - Jemison (Box 18)
  - Jennings - Kellett (Box 19)
  - Kelley - Lude (Box 20)
  - Lepond - Lynde, E. (Box 21)
  - Lynde, S. - Mattoon, C. (Box 22)
  - Mattoon, E. - Mead, Stephen (Box 23)
  - Mead, S. - Miller, J. (Box 24)
  - Miller, M. - Morgan, P. (Box 25)
  - Morgan, R. - Otie (Box 26)
  - Packer - Pick (Box 27)
  - Pierce - Quinn (Box 28)
  - Quinnipiac Fertilizer Co. - Rogers, B. (Box 29)
  - Rogers, C. - Ryley (Box 30)
  - Stafford - Smith, A. (Box 31)
  - Smith, B. - Somers (Box 32)
  - Spalding - Stool (Box 33)
  - Stone - Tinker, John (Box 34)
  - Tinker, Joseph - Watrows, Jared (Box 35)
  - Watrows, John - Winchester (Box 36)
  - Winthrop - Woodruff (Box 37)